A Guide to the Benjamin F. Cooling Manuscript Papers on Historical Highlights of Bull Run Park, 1965-1978
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Benjamin F. Cooling Manuscript Papers on Historical Highlights of Bull Run Park, 1965-1978
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 08-03
.5 linear feet
The Benjamin F. Cooling III Manuscript Papers on Historical Highlights of Bull Run Park consists of .5 linear feet, spans the years 1965-1978, and consists of research material, manuscript drafts, maps, illustrations, and correspondence. Subjects covered are Fairfax County’s Native American and European roots, Fairfax County’s agrarian economy in the early National Period, Civil War activity in the area that is now Bull Run Regional Park, and the development of the town of Clifton.
Cooling III, Benjamin F. (1938-)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Unknown
Historical and Biographical Information
In 1978, the Fairfax County Office of Comprehensive Planning printed the Historical Highlights of Bull Run Park, written by Benjamin F. Cooling III. The book was a cooperative effort by regional and county offices to publish a history of the Bull Run-Occoquan Regional Park area.
Dr. Benjamin Franklin Cooling III is an historian and author of books on the U.S. Civil War. He served as Chief Historian and Research Director with the Department of Energy and as a historian with the Army, Air Force, and National Park Service, and elsewhere. He has taught at numerous universities and is currently a Professor of History at the National Defense University in Washington DC. Cooling has written or edited over 16 books on the Civil War and modern warfare and has written several hundred articles, essays and reviews on aspects of military, naval and other history. His books include The Day Lincoln Was Almost Shot: The Fort Stevens Story (2013), Counter-Thrust: From the Peninsula to the Antietam (Great Campaigns of the Civil War) (2008), USS Olympia: Herald of Empire (2000), Fort Donnelson’s Legacy (1997), Jubal Early’s Raid on Washington (1995), Symbol, Sword and Shield (1991), Forts Henry and Donnelson (1988), and other books. He co-authored, with Walton H. Owen II, Mr. Lincoln’s Forts: The Civil War Forts of Washington, DC (2009).
Adjunct Descriptive Data
HLF Bull Run Power Company; HLF Parks - Northern Virginia Region - Bull Run Region
None
Index Terms
Agrarian Economy in the Early National Period; Bull Run Regional Park; Centreville Military Railroad; Civil War; Clifton, Virginia; History of Bull Run Regional Park; Reconstruction; The First Battle of Bull Run (Manassas); The Second Battle of Bull Run (Manassas); Urbanization
Container List
- Cooling, Benjamin F. - Historical Highlights of Bull Run Regional Park (Preliminary Outline), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cooling, Benjamin F. - Historical Highlights of Bull Run Regional Park (First Draft), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cooling, Benjamin F. - Historical Highlights of Bull Run Regional Park (2nd Revised Draft), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bull Run Park Study. Research Materials, Pre-Colonial Era, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bull Run Park Study. Research Materials, Federal Era, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bull Run Park Study. Research Materials, National Era, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bull Run Park Study. Research Materials, Civil War Era, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bull Run Park Study. Research Materials, 20th Century, 1971, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bull Run Park Study. Research Materials, 20th Century Maps, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bull Run Park Study. Research Materials, Bull Run Power Plant, 1969, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bull Run Park Study. Research Materials, General, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bull Run Park Study. Graphics, Illustrations, etc., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bull Run Park Study. Correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bull Run Park Study. Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Cooling, Benjamin F. - Historical Highlights of Bull Run Regional Park, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bull Run Study. Second Battle of Manassas, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)